Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Photographs
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Copy Photographs, undated; Series IX; 8.1 linear feet (32 boxes)
  - Color Slides
    - Stereograph Photographers and Publishers
      - General stereographs
        - 1870s-1880s (Box 87)
        - 1890s (Box 87)
        - 1900s-1930s (Box 87)
        - California Stereo (Box 87)
        - Best Stereo (Box 87)
        - Misc. Stereographs (Box 87)
    - Photographic Processes, Formats, and Equipment
      Organized under two headings: Processes and Formats, and Equipment
      - Processes and Formats
        - Pre-history (Box 88)
        - Daguerreotypes (Box 88)
        - Ambrotypes (Box 88)
        - Tintypes (Box 88)
        - Case Art (Box 88)
        - Wet plates (Box 88)
        - Frames and jewelry (Box 88)
        - Photo-Jewelry (Box 88)
        - Cartes-de-visite (Box 88)
        - Stereographs (Box 89)
        - Panoramas (Box 89)
        - Postcards (Box 89)
        - Photographic prints with hand coloring, 2 (Box 89)
        - Photograph buttons and Kit (Box 89)
      - Equipment
        - Studios and Equipment (Box 89)
        - Equipment (Box 89)
        - Cameras, advertisements (Box 89)
        - Cameras, miscellaneous (Box 89)
    - California Sites and Subjects
      - Arcata (Box 90)
      - Arcata, depicted in a lithograph under its former name, Union (Box 90)
      - Humboldt County (Box 90)
      - Humboldt County and Klamath (Box 90)
      - Humboldt County drawings (Box 90)
      - Humboldt County early photographers (Box 90)
      - Humboldt County lithographs (Box 90)
      - Humboldt County maps by Joseph Whidbey (Box 90)
      - Humboldt County postcards (Box 90)
      - Lake County (Box 90)
      - Lithographs and art of sites in California (Box 90)
      - Mendocino County (Box 90)
      - Monterey County (Box 90)
      - Northern California Indians (Box 90)
      - Painting of Eureka, California, 1854 (Box 91)
      - Paintings of sites in California (Box 91)
      - Painting of Fort Humboldt, Eureka, California (Box 91)
      - Paintings of the Yosemite Valley, California (Box 91)
      - San Francisco advertisements for photographers (Box 91)
      - Santa Barbara Museum of Art collection photographs (Box 91)
      - Siskiyou County (Box 91)
      - Southern California (Box 91)
      - Yuba County (Box 91)
    - Historical Subjects
      - California Gold Rush (Box 92)
      - Chief Counshin, also known as Ki-we-lat-tah or Kiwelattah, Wiyot Indian leader (Box 92)
      - Civil War (Box 92)
      - Coast Survey (Box 92)
      - Early American photographs (Box 92)
      - Early European photographs (Box 92)
      - George Gibbs and American Indians (Box 92)
    - General Research and Presentations
      - History of photography (Box 93)
      - Photojournalism (Box 93)
      - Photographs of children (Box 93)
      - Photographs of gravestones with photographic portraits (Box 93)
      - Research (Box 93)
      - Slides for presentations
        - American Indians (Box 94)
        - Augustus William Ericson (Box 94)
        - Carleton Watkins (Box 94)
        - Promotion of railways by photographers: A. J. Russell, William Henry Jackson, and Emma Freeman (Box 94)
        - Research and teaching materials documenting Palmquist's work (Box 94)
        - Women in photography (Box 94)
        - Title slides for presentations (Box 94)
    - Slides from Workspace
      Related Archival Materials note
      Organized by location in Palmquist's workspace.
      Slides in this component were originally on a light stand, and on top of a desk and in its drawers, as well as in slide carousels in Palmquist's workspace at the time of his death. The slides chiefly consist of copy photographs of material in his collection.
      Library staff initially housed the slides from the light stand and desk into boxes, which staff then rehoused in three-ring binders with dividers that designate those boxes.
      - No. 1 - Slides from light stand, desk and first drawer (Box 95)
      - No. 2 - Slides from second drawer (Box 95)
      - No. 3 - Slides from second drawer (Box 95)
      - No. 4 - Slides from second and third drawers (Box 96)
      - No. 5 - Slides from third drawer (Box 96)
      - No. 6 - Slides from third drawer (Box 97)
      - No. 7 - Slides from third drawer (Box 97)
      - No. 8 - Slides from fourth drawer (Box 98)
      - No. 9 - Slides from fourth drawer (Box 98)
      - No. 10 - Slides from fourth drawer (Box 99)
      - No. 11 - Slides from fourth drawer (Box 99)
      - No. 12 - Slides from fourth drawer (Box 100)
      - No. 13 - Slides from fourth drawer (Box 100)
      - Slides from carousels, 7 (Box 101)
      - Slides from carousels, 7 (Box 102)
      - Slides from a carousel (Box 103)
- Peter Palmquist Retrospective, circa 1950-2002; Series X; 1.6 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Series I is organized generally chronologically followed by printed material, photograph albums of the Marble Mountain Wilderness, and oversize material.
  Material selected by Rebekah Burgess and Lucy Hilmer in May 2003 for a retrospective project about photography by Palmquist.
  - Portraits of Peter Palmquist (Box 104)
  - United States Army Photographs (Box 104)
  - Personal photographs during military service
    - England (Box 104)
    - France
      - Alone in Paris (Box 104)
      - Captured human exchanges (Box 104)
      - Evocative scenes with and without people (Box 104)
      - Flea markets (Box 104)
      - The Louvre (Box 104)
      - Passing portraits (Box 104)
      - Readers (Box 104)
      - Street artists (Box 104)
    - Italy (Box 104)
    - Malta (Box 104)
    - Morocco (Box 104)
    - Portugal (Box 104)
    - Spain (Box 104)
    - Switzerland (Box 104)
    - Subjects
      - Animals (Box 104)
      - Art and artists (Box 104)
      - Children (Box 104)
      - Color prints (Box 104)
      - Exteriors (Box 104)
      - Human exchanges (Box 104)
      - Interiors (Box 104)
      - Landscapes (Box 104)
      - Portraits (Box 104)
      - Seascapes (Box 104)
      - Street scenes (Box 104)
  - General photographs
    - Arcata, California (Box 104)
    - Christmas Flood of 1964 (Box 104)
    - Color prints (Box 104)
    - Exterior details (Box 104)
    - Forests (Box 104)
    - Humboldt State College, Theater Arts Department (Box 104)
    - Japan (Box 104)
    - Lumber mill (Box 104)
    - Nudes, 3 (Box 104)
    - Portrait of a woman (Box 104)
    - Pottery (Box 104)
    - Seascapes (Box 104)
  - Printed Material
    - Magazines (Box 104)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 104)
  - Photograph Albums of the Marble Mountain Wilderness
    Photographs albums that document hiking excursions into the Marble Mountain Wilderness in Klamath National Forest, California.
    - Photograph album, circa 1950 (Box 105)
    - Photograph album, "Peter Palmquist's Marble Mountain AFS Wilderness Hike", 2002 May 25-27 (Box 105)
      Palmquist and others led a group of foreign exchange high school students involved in the American Field Service programs.
  - Oversize
    - Portraits of Peter Palmquist (Box 106)
    - Personal photographs during military service
      - England, 3 (Box 106)
      - France, 2 (Box 106)
      - Malta, 2 (Box 106)
        - General photographs
          - Arcata, California (Box 107)
          - Camping (Box 107)
          - Christmas flood of 1964, 12 (Box 107)
          - Exterior details, 3 (Box 107)
          - Hilltopper page mock-ups for an unidentified story, circa 1966; 7 (Box 107)
            Hilltopper was a publication of Humboldt State College, 1959-1993.
          - Humboldt State College football player, 1963 (Box 107)
          - Johnson, Claudia "Lady Bird," at the dedication of the Lady Bird Johnson Grove in Redwood National Park, 1969 August 27 (Box 107)
          - Nudes, 2 (Box 107)
          - Portrait of a fortune teller (Box 107)
          - Portraits of women (Box 107)
          - Redwood forests, 2 (Box 107)
          - Seascapes, 2 (Box 107)
      - Switzerland (Box 106)
      - Subjects
        - Animals (Box 106)
        - Children, 4 (Box 106)
        - Cloudscapes (Box 106)
        - Interiors, 2 (Box 106)
        - Pottery (Box 106)
        - Street scenes, 4 (Box 106)
- Oversize Photographs, 1957-1995; Series XI; 0.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Series XI is organized into six subseries: United States Army Photographs, Personal Photographs During Military Service, General Photographs, Collected Photographs, and Peter Palmquist Retrospective.
  Oversize photographic material larger than 18 inches in size and smaller than 24 inches, which document photography created and collected by Palmquist, as well as exhibitions.
  - United States Army Photographs
    - Baseball (Box 108 (Oversize))
    - Military installation (Box 108 (Oversize))
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization leaders, circa 1957 (Box 108 (Oversize))
    - Royal Navy aircraft carrier (Box 108 (Oversize))
  - Personal Photographs During Military Service
    - Desert landscape, probably Morocco (Box 108 (Oversize))
    - Switzerland (Box 108 (Oversize))
  - General Photographs
    - Portrait of Peter Palmquist (Box 109 (Oversize))
    - Ferndale, California; Ferndale Cemetery (Box 109 (Oversize))
    - Flock of sheep, probably in Malta (Box 110 (Broadside))
    - Humboldt State University, Theater Arts Department, Images for a brochure (Box 111 (Broadside))
    - Humboldt State College Theater Arts Department, 1962-1972; 19 (Box 109 (Oversize))
    - Nudes, 5 (Box 109 (Oversize))
    - Portraits of women (Box 109 (Oversize))
    - San Francisco, California, rephotograph of a panoramic view from Rincon Hill, circa 1985 (Box 112 (Broadside))
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Image created from nearly the same location as a view of San Francisco from Rincon Hill, circa 1851, from a copy photograph of a daguerreotype panorama that Martin Behrman created circa 1910.
    - Still lifes (Box 109 (Oversize))
    - Studio of Elmo Seely, circa 1983; 8 (Box 113 (Oversize))
      Chiefly photographs by Palmquist that document the studio of Elmo Seely in Arcata, California, that formed part of an exhibition, Seely Studio: The Tradition Continues at Humboldt State University, Arcata, California, in 1984 with fellow photographer Dar Spain, which commemorated Seely's fifty years as a commercial photographer. This component also includes the artists' statements for the exhibition.
  - Collected Photographs
    - Bob Erickson, Panoramic photographic of attendees of the International 3D Festival, Atlanta, Georgia, 1995 (Box 114 (Broadside))
    - Copy of a panoramic view of San Francisco from Rincon Hill, circa 1851 (Box 115 (Broadside))
  - Peter Palmquist Retrospective
    Oversize material selected by Rebekah Burgess and Lucy Hilmer in May 2003 for a retrospective project about photography by Palmquist.
    - Portraits of Peter Palmquist, 2 (Box 116 (Oversize))
    - Personal photographs during military service
      - England (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - France (Box 116 (Oversize))
    - General photographs
      - Exterior details, 3 (Box 116 (Oversize))
    - Hilltopper page mock-ups
      - Dan Bryant and Peter E. Palmquist. "Palmquist Meets Paris." Hilltopper 6, no. 1, 1961 (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - Peter E. Palmquist and Terry Aitken. "Pamplona." Hilltopper 6, no. 2, 1962 (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - Unrealized article on L'Abbaye, Switzerland (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - Unrealized article on The Louvre (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - Unrealized article on Malta (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - Unrealized article on Yves Klein (Box 116 (Oversize))
- Additions from Other Collections, Series XII
  - Humboldt State University Theater Arts Department
    - Departmental brochure mock-up, circa 1960 (Box 117)
    - Department brochure, 1965 (Box 117)
    - Department season schedule, 1965-1966 (Box 117)
    - Brochure, 1968 (Box 117)
    - Creative dramatics and puppetry program, circa 1968-1969 (Box 117)
    - Mime and experimental theater, circa 1969-1970 (Box 117)
    - Program, Animal, The Witchery of the Butterfly, and Bedtime Story, 1971 March (Box 117)
  - General Photographs
    - Photographic prints, Portraits in children, women, and men wearing nineteenth century costume, circa 1976 (Box 117)
    - Photographic prints, Interior portraits of women (Box 118)
    - Transparencies
      - Guitar player on railroad tracks (Box 117)
      - Metalsmithing (Box 117)
      - Paintings by Helen Dora Lemprière (Box 117)
      - Paris, France, street scenes (Box 117)
      - Potter (Box 117)
      - Sierra Nevada region, California (Box 117)
    - Negative, street scene (Box 117)